[Respect Copyright, Everyone's Responsibility]
[정품을 보호하는 것은 우리 모두의 책임입니다]
[The Eternal Fragrance]
[천향] [십사랑 소설 '천향인' 각색 작품]
[Episode 11]
[제11화]
Once I've honed my spirit power
내 영력이 정진하여
and mastered the technique,
술법을 완성하게 되면
she'll never be hurt by anyone again,
그 아이는 영원히 그 누구에게도 다치지 않을 것이다
not even me.
나를 포함해서 말이지
Good thing the masters discovered it in time.
선생들께서 제때 발견해 주신 덕분입니다
That wretch from the Sea Sect
그 해파의 요녀가 가짜 신분으로 위장하여
had been hiding among us under a false identity.
우리 문파에 이토록 오랫동안 잠입해 있었다니요
She must have been trying to steal
분명 우리 산파의
our secret manuals and treasures.
비책과 법보를 훔치려 한 게 틀림없습니다
So devious.
참으로 간계가 변화무쌍하군요
Those Sea Sect scoundrels
해파의 요인들은 원래
love practicing these twisted arts.
그런 외도의 사악한 법술이나 수련하길 좋아하지
No wonder she had demonic energy on her.
그 요녀에게서 마기가 흘러나온 것도 이상할 게 없네
The masters are too soft.
선생들께서도 참으로 유약하시지
For someone like that,
그런 요사스러운 자들은
we should torture them
엄형에 처해 자백을 받아내야 하거늘
to see if they have other schemes.
다른 꿍꿍이가 있는지 엄히 따져 물었어야지
That female master
그 여부자 님은
taught us technique class for months.
지난 몇 달 동안 우리에게 술법을 가르쳐 주신 분이야
By that logic,
네 말대로라면
are we all scoundrels
그분께 배운 우리 모두가
practicing twisted arts too?
외도의 사술을 익힌 요인이란 말인가?
Yeah.
그러게 말입니다
Ms. Lin was strict,
임 선생님께서 평소에 조금 엄격하시긴 했어도
but she never harmed any of us.
단 한 번도 우리를 해치신 적은 없었습니다
She taught us well
정성을 다해 가르쳐 주셨을 뿐 아니라
and even helped us in the last trial.
지난번 시련 때도 저희를 도와주셨지요
Since the headmaster hasn't said anything,
원장님께서도 아무 말씀이 없으신데
some people should drop their prejudice
어떤 이들은 편견에 사로잡혀
and stop piling on.
남이 어려움에 처하자 돌을 던지는군요
Those not of our kind
우리와 부류가 다르면
are of different mind.
그 마음 또한 반드시 다른 법이지
You call those treacherous villains your master?
정체를 숨긴 흉악한 요괴를 스승이라 부르다니
What,
설마 너희도
are you in league with demons too?
마족과 한패가 되려는 것이냐?
You...
너
I mean, the situation isn't clear yet.
아직 진상이 밝혀지지 않았으니
Don't slander good people.
함부로 선한 사람을 모함하지 말거라
Good people?
선한 사람이라고?
When the Sea Calamity struck,
당년 해운이 세상을 뒤덮었을 때
countless cultivators
각 선문이 마족을 막아내기 위해
died fighting demons.
얼마나 많은 이들을 희생했는지 잊었느냐
Now the Sea Sect openly wields demonic tools
지금 해파는 대놓고 요물들을 부리며
and forges demonic artifacts.
마기를 제련하고 있다
Anyone who sides with demons can't be good.
마족과 한패인 자치고 어찌 선한 사람일 수 있겠어?
Anyone tied to demons
마족과 조금이라도 얽힌 자들은
is a villain!
전부 다른 부류의 요괴일 뿐이다
Tongzhou.
사촌 오라버니
Am I right?
제 말이 맞지 않습니까?
When the demons invaded,
당년 마족이 침해했을 때
the Central Plains sects were nearly wiped out.
중원의 선문들은 거의 전멸하다시피 했다
Of the elders of Xingzheng Hall,
성정관의 장로들도 두 분을 제외하고는
only two survived.
모두 희생되셨지
But the Sea Sect kept a vague stance
허나 해파는 입장을 모호히 취하여
and escaped the catastrophe.
큰 화를 면했다
They might not be enemies,
그들이 비록 적은 아닐지라도
but they're not friends either.
결코 가까이해서는 안 될 자들이다
Yecha's whereabouts?
야차 행방이라니요
Did one of your ancestors
너희 조상 중에 혹시
die at Yecha's hands?
야차의 손에 죽은 자라도 있는 게냐?
Are you seeking revenge?
그자에게 복수라도 하려는 게야?
We just want to know where the Demon Lord is.
우리는 그저 마군이 어디에 있는지 알고 싶을 뿐입니다
He was destroyed five hundred years ago.
그분은 오백 년 전에 이미 혼비백산하여 소멸하셨다
If Yecha were still alive,
만일 야차가 아직 살아있었다면
he wouldn't allow his broken horns
잘려 나간 뿔이
to be used as artifacts of the Sea Sect.
우리 해파의 법구로 쓰이는 것을 가만두었겠느냐?
Come to think of it,
그러고 보니
you Gaolu people have always had
너희 고로 일족은 예부터
an ambiguous stance toward demons.
마족을 대하는 태도가 애매했지
I heard that during the Sea Calamity,
듣자 하니 지난 해운 때
disciples from Gaolu
고로의 제자 하나가
tried to cross the mountain-sea barrier.
산해결계를 넘어가려 했다던데
Could you
설마
have some connection to demons?
너희가 마족과 무슨 인연이라도 있는 것이냐?
Since it's an ancestral charge,
선조의 유명이니
the Divine Lord's soul probably won't dissipate so easily.
신군의 혼백이 쉽게 흩어졌을 리는 없습니다
We'll keep searching.
천천히 더 찾아보시지요
Who's there?
누구냐
Gelin?
가림아
I looked for you for practice, but couldn't find you.
무공을 수련하려고 하는데 아무리 찾아도 보이지 않더니
Turns out Ye...
역시나
Turns out you two were here.
언니와 엽 오라버니께서 모두 여기 계셨군요
Didn't we say that the three of us stick together?
셋이서 늘 함께하기로 약조해 놓고
Why do you always leave me out?
어찌 매번 저만 따돌리시는 겁니까?
We didn't mean to.
일부러 너를 빼놓은 것은 아니니라
It's just that there are things...
다만 몇 가지 일이
we haven't figured out ourselves.
우리도 아직 분명히 알지 못하는 터라
We didn't want to worry you.
네가 걱정할까 하여 말하지 않았을 뿐이니라
I didn't mean to pry into your secrets.
저도 일부러 언니와 오라버니의 비밀을 알아내려 한 것은 아니었어요
I was just... worried about you.
저, 저도 두 분이 걱정되어서 그런 것이란 말이에요
Gelin,
가림아
it's my fault.
다 내 잘못이구나
We're family.
우리가 한가족이 아닙니까?
Family can't be wrong.
가족 사이에 어찌 잘못을 따지겠습니까
What's that?
저것은 무엇입니까?
Mr. Zuo Qiu,
좌구 선생님
Jiao acted recklessly
아초가 잠시 미혹에 빠져
and caused trouble at the academy.
서원에 들어와 소란을 일으켰습니다
It's my fault for not keeping my daughter in check.
이는 모두 딸을 제대로 단속하지 못한 제 탓입니다
Mr. Shen,
심 선생님
I was weak before.
이전에는 제 뜻이 확고하지 못하여
I was afraid I couldn't protect her.
이 아이를 끝까지 지켜낼 수 없을까 두려웠습니다
Now I've come to realize
허나 이제는 알게 되었습니다
that hesitation
앞뒤를 재고 망설이며
and indecision
우유부단하게 굴던 그 마음이야말로
hurt the most.
사람을 가장 깊이 상하게 한다는 것을요
[Mr. Shen, Wanxian Sect] I'll follow my heart
[만선문 심 선생] 저는 이제 마음이 이끄는 대로 살고자 합니다
and go to the East Sea with Jiao.
아초를 따라 동해로 가겠습니다
I'll spend the rest of my life protecting her.
남은 생을 다하여 아초의 안녕과 기쁨을 지키겠습니다
Yanfan.
언범아
Mr. Zuo Qiu,
좌구 선생님
what is this all about?
대체 이게 어찌 된 일입니까?
The division between the Mountain and Sea Sects
산파와 해파의 경계란
is just human prejudice.
본디 사람 마음의 편견에서 비롯된 것
If someone has the courage to break through those barriers,
스스로 마음을 내어 그 장벽을 허물고자 한다면
it can be a beautiful thing.
이 또한 한 편의 아름다운 가화가 아니겠는가
Isn't Jiao a wretch from the Sea Sect?
아초가 해파의 요녀라고 하지 않으셨습니까?
Why would Mr. Mo be with her?
묵 선생님께서는 어찌하여 그 여인과 함께 계신 것입니까?
Mr. Mo is really leaving?
묵 선생님마저 떠나신다면
Then who's going to teach us artifact crafting?
그럼 이제 누가 저에게 연기를 가르쳐 주십니까?
Bu said
부 사형께서 말씀하지 않으셨습니까
the Sea Calamity is coming,
해운이 임박하였으니
and the Mountain and Sea Sects
산해 양파는 마땅히 한마음으로 힘을 합쳐
must unite against it.
함께 적을 막아야 한다고요
He also said
또 결업 때에는
that when we graduate,
동해에서 사람을 보내
people from the East Sea will be here to recruit.
제자를 선발한다고 하셨으니
Maybe we'll see him again then.
그때면 다시 뵐 기회도 있을 것입니다
Mee at the East Sea?
동해에 가서 뵙는다고요?
Nonsense!
터무니없는 소리, 당치도 않다
How could we possibly join forces?
어찌 연합을 한단 말이야?
Mr. Mo was a top disciple of Xingzheng Hall.
묵 선생님은 성정관의 고제이시거늘
He would never side with a wretch.
결코 저런 요녀와 뜻을 같이할 분이 아니다
She must have bewitched him.
분명 저 요녀에게 미혹당하신 게 틀림없어
Tongzhou,
사촌 오라버니
let's tell Mr. Xuanshan
아무래도 이 일을 어서
about this.
현산 백부님께 고해야겠습니다
He already knows.
허나 백부님께선 이미 알고 계신다
- Then what did he say...? - I've failed Master.
- 그럼 백부님께서 뭐라고 하시던가요? - 내가 스승의 은혜를 저버렸다
From today on,
오늘 이후로
I am no longer a disciple of Xingzheng Hall.
나는 더 이상 성정관의 제자가 아니다
You two really made up?
두 분께서는 정말 화해하신 것입니까?
I'm going to the East Sea with Jiao.
내가 아초와 함께 동해로 떠나면
I don't know when I'll see you all again.
다음 만남이 기약이 없을 터
Before I go,
떠나기 전에
let me break your Fragrance Bond.
너희에게 얽힌 천향인을 풀어주마
You want to break the Fragrance Bond?
천향인을 풀겠다고?
♪The warmth within my arms♪
♪품 안에 가득했던 그대의 온기♪
♪I can no longer hold on to♪
♪내 이제는 끝내 붙잡지 못하네♪
We're parting ways anyway.
어차피 헤어질 사이인데
It's useless now.
남겨두어 어디에 쓰겠습니까?
Might as well break it.
푸는 편이 낫지요
♪In the cold night, how can I♪
♪시린 이 겨울밤, 그대를 어떻게 다시♪
♪Keep you warm until sunrise?♪
♪동이 틀 때까지 따스히 품어줄까♪
♪My heartbeat freezes♪
♪가슴은 차갑게 얼어붙고♪
♪I can no longer tell you♪
♪마음을 전할 길조차 없는데♪
Please, Mr. Mo.
부탁드리겠습니다, 선생님
♪Looking you in the eyes, I cannot♪
♪그대 눈을 보며 하려던 그 한마디♪
♪Utter that line♪
♪끝내 입 밖으로 내지 못하네♪
♪Knowing right and wrong♪
♪애증과 아픔, 깊어진 상처가♪
♪Black and gray are all illusions♪
♪검고 흐린 세상사 모두 부질없거늘♪
♪You're still screaming♪
♪그대는 여전히 목놓아 울부짖으며♪
♪Running relentlessly without regret♪
♪미련 없이 거칠게 발버둥 치는구나♪
♪The storm looms, yet the wind stand in its way♪
♪몰아치는 비바람 온몸으로 막아서며♪
♪A final farewell left on the cliff♪
♪절벽 끝자락에 눈물로 새긴 서약♪
♪Leaping straight into that heartbreaking past♪
♪내 기꺼이 이 몸을 던지리라 살을 도려내는 듯한 아픈 기억 속으로♪
♪Just to keep you safe♪
♪그대만 무사할 수 있다면♪
♪My breath is about to stop♪
♪내 숨결이 점차 희미해지고♪
♪Those hands can no longer hold yours♪
♪맞잡은 그 손을 더는 쥘 수 없으니♪
♪Through the future snow, wind, and fog♪
♪앞으로 다가올 시린 바람과 안개를♪
♪Who will be there by your side?♪
♪이제 누구와 함께 견뎌내야 할까♪
♪I smile as it ends♪
♪미소를 지으며 눈을 감는 것은♪
♪Afraid that you might cry for me♪
♪나로 인해 그대 슬피 울까 염려되어♪
♪Quietly, I turn into a sky lantern♪
♪말없이 공명등 한 줄기 빛이 되어♪
♪To light your way through the night♪
♪그대가 걷는 어두운 밤길을 비추어주리♪
♪Knowing right and wrong♪
♪옳고 그름도, 흑백의 경계도♪
♪Black and gray are all illusions♪
♪검고 흐린 세상사 모두 부질없거늘♪
♪You're still screaming♪
♪그대는 여전히 목놓아 울부짖으며♪
♪Running relentlessly without regret♪
♪미련 없이 거칠게 발버둥 치는구나♪
What's wrong?
어찌 그러하십니까?
Strange.
기이하구나
It won't break.
풀리지 않는구나
Unresolved attachments
마음속 집착이 사라지지 않으니
make the bond unbreakable.
인연의 끈 또한 끊어내기 어려운 법이지
You three share deep feelings for each other.
너희 세 사람은 분명 서로를 향한 정이 깊이 얽혀 있구나
♪To lay all your days in peace♪
♪남은 네 생이 부디 평탄하기를♪
♪Who says that love and hate♪
♪그 누가 말했나, 사랑과 미움♪
♪Pain and wounds cannot be stopped?♪
♪밀려드는 고통과 상처를 막을 수 없음을 알면서도♪
You just won't give up, will you?
결국 너는 미련을 버리지 못하는구나
♪I will level the seas and mountains♪
♪내 저 산과 바다를 평정하고♪
Forget it.
됐다
♪Break the waves, no matter how mad it seems♪
♪풍랑을 부수리니 미쳐 날뛴대도 무엇이 두려우랴♪
♪The storm looms, yet I stand in its way♪
♪닥쳐오는 비바람을 내 기어이 가로막으리♪
If the feelings were only one-sided,
만약 한쪽만 무정했다면
it would break.
풀어낼 수 있었을 터인데
Since it won't,
풀리지 않는다는 것은
it only shows the three of you
바로 너희 세 사람 모두가
truly care for each other.
서로를 마음 깊이 위하고 있기 때문이다
Young people always fail to see their true feelings.
젊은이들은 늘 자신의 마음을 제대로 보지 못하는 법이지
Ye, hello.
사형, 안녕하셨습니까?
Gelin.
가림아
I... I have things to do.
저, 저 아직 할 일이 남아서
I'm leaving.
먼저 가볼게요
Time flies.
시간이 참 빠르군요
Lifei,
려비 낭자
you said you wanted to join Wuyue Court.
지난번 무월정으로 간다 하셨던 일
Are you confident?
확실히 해낼 수 있으십니까?
Wuyue Court is the number one immortal sect in the world.
무월정은 말이다, 천하 제일의 선문이라 하지 않더냐
Some people have average talent
허나 어떤 이는 타고난 자질도 평범하고
and can't even use their spirit power properly,
영력마저 제대로 쓰지 못하면서
yet they still dream of getting into Wuyue Court?
어찌 감히 무월정에 들 수 있겠느냐
At least we'll try with our own abilities.
적어도 우리는 제 힘으로 부딪쳐 볼 것이야
Unlike some people
누구들처럼 배경을 등에 업고
who rely on connections.
가문의 연줄에 기대지는 않지
Connections?
가문의 연줄이라니?
We are of imperial blood.
우리는 본디 귀한 황실의 핏줄이거늘
We belong in Xingzheng Hall.
성정관에 드는 것이 당연하지 않겠느냐
As for you,
오히려 너희들 말이다
Gaolu offended Longming Sanctuary.
고로가 용명좌의 눈 밖에 난 지금
Which sect do you think
과연 어느 선문이
would still accept you?
감히 너희를 받아주겠느냐?
You...
너
Lanya.
란아야
What, did I say something wrong?
어찌 그러세요? 제가 틀린 말 했나요?
Not every cultivation sect fears Longming Sanctuary.
모든 수선 문파가 용명좌를 두려워하는 것은 아니고
And not every cultivator
또한 도를 닦는 자라 해서
is a bootlicker.
모두가 권세에 아부하는 것도 아니야
I heard there's a new sect in Xizhou called Dizang Sect.
듣자하니 서주에 지장문이라는 신흥 문파가 하나 생겼다 하는데
They specialize in stealth
은신과
and transformation.
변화를 능하게 다룬다 합니다
They've taken in many people from Gaolu.
또한 고로국 출신자들을 상당수 받아들였다 하지요
Xiuyuan,
수원아
where do you plan to go?
자네는 어디로 갈 생각인가?
I'm going back to study.
난 이만 물러가 책을 읽겠습니다
Lifei!
려비야
Take this.
이것을 받아두거라
What is it?
무엇입니까?
Sanctuary of Dragons and Phoenixes?
용서봉림
What dragon and phoenix?
용이니 봉황이니 하는 걸 보니
Is this some imperial token?
황실의 신물입니까?
With this, you'll have
이것을 지니고 월국에 가면
the same authority as me in the Yue State.
내 친히 걸음 한 것과 다름없으니
It'll make things easier for you.
무슨 일을 도모하든 방도가 편할 터다
Why would I go to Yue?
멀쩡히 잘 있는데 제가 굳이 월국에 갈 까닭이 있겠습니까?
Lifei,
려비야
you're going to Wuyue Court
네가 무월정에 가려는 것은
to find your master, right?
네 사부님을 찾기 위함이 아니더냐
But you don't have to
사부님을 찾기 위해
go to Wuyue Court for him yourself.
반드시 무월정까지 갈 필요는 없느니라
I can help you look for him.
내가 사람을 풀어 찾아줄 수도 있으니
Wait for my news in Yue.
너는 그저 월국에서 내 소식을 기다리려무나
His Majesty
내 황형께서는
is kind and warm-hearted.
성품이 온화하고 정이 많으신 분이라
You can eat or do whatever
네가 무엇을 먹고 싶든, 무엇을 즐기고 싶든
you want there.
다 네 뜻대로 해줄 터다
This is too valuable.
이건 과분하게 귀중한 물건이라
I can't accept it.
받을 수 없습니다
Why?
어찌 그러느냐?
Take it.
그냥 받아두거라
Finding my master is my own business.
사부님을 찾는 일은 제 개인적인 일이니
I can't let someone else do it for me.
타인의 손을 빌려 해결할 수는 없습니다
Take it back.
받으라니까 그러는구나
Lifei.
려비야
After I find my master,
저는 사부님을 찾고 나면
I'll go back to Qingqiu with him.
스승님과 함께 청구로 돌아갈 생각입니다
Besides, you have your own missions.
그리고 해야 하실 일이 있지 않습니까?
You need to go to Xingzheng Hall
성정관으로 가셔서
and win over all those
그간 그대를 못마땅하게 여기던
who oppose you.
현문과 화문 등을 모두 굴복시키고
You need to make Yue
또 월국과 성정관을
and Xingzheng Hall prosper.
널리 떨쳐야 하지 않겠습니까
But for you, I would...
허나 난 너를 위해서라면 기꺼이...
I don't want that.
저는 원치 않습니다
Tongzhou,
동주 공자
you're a prince.
그대는 왕야이십니다
You carry so many burdens and expectations.
몸에 짊어진 짐과 기대가 얼마나 무거운지 잘 알고 계시지 않습니까
But I'm different.
하지만 저는 다릅니다
I just want to live an ordinary life with my master.
저는 그저 사부님과 함께 평범한 나날을 보내며
Just food on the table,
배불리 먹고 편히 지내다
and a peaceful end.
평온히 생을 마감하는 것입니다
We're not meant to walk the same path.
우리는 결국, 같은 길을 갈 수 없는 사람들입니다
You're not willing now.
지금은 뜻이 다를지라도
What about later?
훗날은 어찌 알겠느냐?
What if you change your mind someday...
혹여 나중에 마음이 바뀔지도 모르는 일이지
Later?
훗날이라니요
When you go to Xingzheng Hall,
성정관에 들어가면
princesses and fairies will flock around you.
내로라하는 공주들과 선녀들이 주변을 맴돌 터인데
You'll be so happy
그때가 되면 분명 즐거움에 빠져 고향도 잊고
that you'll forget all about me.
저 같은 존재는 가장 먼저 잊어버리실 것이 뻔합니다
With the Fragrance Bond as witness
천향이 인연의 줄이 되고
and Chufeng Academy as proof,
추봉이 증표가 되리니
I will never forget you.
난 결코 너를 잊지 않을 것이다
It's just a childhood game.
그저 철없던 소년 시절의 장난이었을 뿐인데
Not worth remembering for a lifetime.
평생토록 가슴에 새겨둘 일이라 할 수 있겠습니까
Prince Ying,
영왕 전하
when Xingzheng Hall becomes
훗날 성정관이
the number one immortal sect,
천하 제일의 선문이 되는 날
I'll come to you for a toast,
반드시 찾아뵈어 축하의 술을 청할 것입니다
wishing you a bright future
전하의 앞날이 비단길 같기를
and eternal glory.
그리고 만세의 대업을 이루시기를 기원하겠습니다
Tongzhou.
사촌 오라버니
That token is meant for your future wife.
그 용서봉림은 미래의 영왕비께 드릴 물건이 아닙니까?
Why did you give it to Jiang Lifei?
헌데 어찌하여 강려비에게 주시는 것입니까?
Because I like her.
그 아이를 마음에 품었기 때문이다
You like her?
그 아이를 좋아하신다는 말씀이십니까?
What do you even see in her?
도대체 무엇을 보고 그러하시는 것입니까?
She has no background, and no skills.
가문이 뛰어난 것도 아니고, 특출난 능력이 있는 것도 아니지 않습니까
She's rude.
더구나 무례하기 짝이 없고
And she's greedy for money!
재물에 눈이 밝은 탐욕스러운 아이인데 말입니다
Lanya,
란아야
she's really different from anyone else.
그 아이는 다른 이들과는 확연히 다르단다
I've never wanted to be with someone
누군가와 이토록 간절하
so badly before.
곁에 두고 싶다 느낀 것은 내 평생 처음이야
Tongzhou,
사촌 오라버니
His Majesty already approved our engagement.
황 오라버니께서도 이미 우리의 혼약을 묵인하셨거늘
Aren't you supposed to marry me?
장차 아내로 맞이할 사람은 제가 아닙니까?
Besides,
게다가
what's the point of thinking about her?
오라버니가 그 아이를 마음에 둔들 무슨 소용입니까?
She doesn't think about you at all!
그 아이의 마음속에는 처음부터 오라버니는 눈곱만큼도 없었습니다
I see.
알겠습니다
She must have used
그 아이가 분명 오라버니에게
some cheap trick on you.
비열한 수작을 부려
She put a mind-control spell on you, right?
미혼주라도 숨겨 둔 것이 틀림없습니다
Where is it? Where?
어디 있습니까? 어디에 숨긴 겁니까?
Lanya.
란아야
Sit down.
단정히 앉거라
Tongzhou,
사촌 오라버니
think carefully.
잘 생각해 보십시오
We've known each other for over ten years.
저와 오라버니는 십여 년을 함께한 정이 있지 않습니까
You've known her for...
그 아이와는 고작
less than a year!
일 년도 채 되지 않았습니다
Alright.
알겠다, 알겠다
Let's focus on the graduation exam first.
가서 수료 시험 준비나 하거라
I'm done preparing!
무슨 준비를 하라는 말씀이십니까?
If I can't marry you,
영왕비 자리도 놓치게 생겼는데
why bother taking the exam?
시험은 보아 무엇 합니까
I'm not taking it!
저는 보지 않겠습니다
Everyone, run!
모두 피하라
What's that sound?
이, 이게 대체 무슨 소리지?
It's Gugu Chicken.
구구닭이다
Gugu Chicken is warning us.
구구닭이 경고를 보내고 있습니다
It says...
녀석 말로는
Everyone, run!
모두 피하십시오
Why is there miasma in the academy?
서원에 어찌 장기가 들이닥친 것이지?
There's demonic energy!
마기다
No, it's demonic energy!
아니다, 마기다
Demonic energy?
마기라니
Hurry!
어서, 어서
Everyone head to Hongyang Hall!
속히 홍양전으로 가세
Go find the masters!
어서 선생님들을 불러오십시오
Bu.
보 사형
Don't move!
움직이지 마라
Tongzhou,
동주야
light the way.
길을 비추게
Let's go.
가세
Watch out!
조심하거라
Lifei!
려비 낭자
Are you okay?
괜찮으십니까?
Where did this demonic fog come from?
이 마무들은 대체 어디서 흘러나온단 말이냐?
Could the demons have invaded?
설마 마족이 침입한 것입니까?
Were the masters all killed?
설마 선생님들께서도 변을 당하신 것은 아니겠지요?
We can't count on the masters.
더는 선생들께 의지할 수 없으니
We need to leave now.
어서 이곳을 벗어나야 할 것이야
Baishan Hall hasn't been corrupted by demonic energy yet.
백선당 쪽은 아직 마기가 침범하지 않은듯 합니다
Our artifacts are failing.
법보가 효력을 잃어
Can't fly on our swords.
어검을 부릴 수 없습니다
How do we get there?
어찌 건너가야 하지요?
We don't know what happened
원장님과 다른 선생들께서는
to Mr. Zuo and the other masters.
과연 무사하신지 모르겠군요
Lifei.
려비야
How did you summon the rainbow deer?
저 홍록을 어찌 소환한 것이냐?
I saw Ms. Mu do it before.
전에 아모 선생께서 소환하시는 걸 본 적이 있습니다
It's called the spirit-summoning spell.
환령술이라 하는데
Anything with spirit should be able to hear it.
영성을 지닌 존재라면 모두 부름을 알아듣는다고 합니다
I never expected
서원에 남은 것이
that only it remains here.
홍록뿐일 줄은 몰랐습니다
Tongzhou!
사촌 오라버니
Who set up this barrier here?
누가 이곳에 결계를 쳐놓은 것이지?
By this talisman,
영부의 인도를 받아
evil spirits reveal themselves.
요괴는 정체를 드러내어라
Go!
하랏
[Xiangxiang]
[향향]
What kind of creature is this?
어디서 온 요괴냐?
Don't hurt her!
해치지 마십시오
Here.
자
She's Mr. Hu's spiritual pet, Xiangxiang.
이 아이는 호 선생님의 영총 향향입니다
Spiritual pet?
영총이라고?
Looks more like a nasty monster to me.
내가 보기엔 그저 괘씸한 소요에 불과하거늘
Monsters aren't necessarily worse than humans.
요괴라고 해서 사람보다 간악하란 법은 없다
Some ungrateful people
은혜를 원수로 갚는 어떤 인간들이
are far worse.
요괴보다 훨씬 더 사악하지
Oh really?
그래?
How so?
그걸 어찌 그리 장담하는 것이냐?
You there.
넌 어찌 그리 뻔뻔하냐?
Lifei was reaching for you.
려비는 분명 너를 붙잡아 주려 했거늘
Why did you push her?
어찌하여 밀쳐낸 게냐?
I pushed her?
내가 밀쳤다고?
Why don't you say
그럼 어찌하여
she just lost her footing?
제 발로 중심을 잃었다고는 하지 않는 것이냐?
Xiangxiang, don't be scared.
향향아, 두려워 말거라
We're Mr. Hu's disciples.
우리는 모두 호 선생님의 제자들이니
We won't hurt you.
결코 너를 해치지 않을 것이다
Tell us,
혹 우리에게 말해 줄 수 있겠느냐?
did you set up this barrier?
이 결계는 네가 펼친 것이냐?
How did you know
이 결계가 마기를 막아낼 수 있다는 것은
it could block demonic energy?
어찌 알았느냐?
I heard it from Mr. Hu.
호 선생님께 들었을 뿐이에요
He told me to set up this formation
선생님께서 위험한 일이 생기거든
if danger comes.
이 법진을 펼치라 하셨어요
What else did Mr. Hu say?
그 밖에 호 선생께서 또 무슨 말씀을 하시더냐?
He said
선생님께서 말씀하시길
there's a sword-forging terrace to the southeast.
동남쪽에 초검대가 있는데
It contains the Sunflare Fire
그곳에 깃든 양염의 불이
that can burn away all evil things.
부정한 기운을 모조리 불살라 없앨 수 있다 하셨어요
I've heard of the Sunflare Fire.
양염의 불에 대해 나도 들은 바가 있다
It can incinerate demonic energy.
마기를 불살라 없앨 수 있다고 하지
The sword-forging terrace is the farthest from Baishan Peak.
초검대는 백선봉에서 가장 먼 곳에 있고
And the path there is covered in demonic fog.
가는 길 내내 마무가 자욱하지
Tongzhou,
사촌 오라버니
news of the academy being attacked
서원이 마족의 기습을 받았다는 소식은
will spread.
분명 밖으로 전해졌을 것입니다
His Majesty
제 생각에는
will probably
황 오라버니께서 머지않아
send someone for us soon.
우리를 구하러 사람을 보내실 터이니
We should stay here
지금은 이곳에 머물며
and not act rashly.
경거망동하지 않는 것이 좋겠습니다
But my power is too weak.
하지만 저는 법력이 너무 약해서
This barrier can only hold for two hours.
이 결계는 고작 한 시진밖에 버티지 못합니다
I'll go with you.
내 너와 동행하마
Let's go find the Sunflare Fire.
우리가 양염의 불을 찾아올 터이니
You must stay here
그대들은 반드시 이곳을 지키며
and wait for rescue.
구원하러 올 때까지 버티십시오
If we can't work together,
우리가 마음을 하나로 모으지 않는다면
we'll never make it out.
이곳을 살아서 빠져나가긴 어려울 것이네
Let's cooperate
우선 힘을 합칩시다
and get through this first.
이 고비를 넘긴 뒤 다시 논하도록 하지요
The sword-forging terrace!
초검대
The Sunflare
얌염이
has died out?
이미 꺼져 버렸구나
The defensive formation is about to fail.
방어진이 곧 무너질 것이네
Hurry!
서둘러야 하네
Tongzhou,
동주 공자
think about
양염에 관한 이야기를 어디에서 들으셨는지
where you heard about the Sunflare.
잘 떠올려 보십시오
How do we ignite it?
어찌해야 양염에 불을 붙일 수 있습니까?
Once, Bu had us study in the library.
한 번은 보 사형께서 우리에게 장서각에서 자습하라 하셨을 때
I found a book in the attic.
다락에서 책 한권을 발견했는데
It said
그 책에 적히기를
the Sunflare is a spiritual flame.
양염은 본디 신령한 불꽃이라
It requires several people to channel their spirit power together
여럿이 마음과 힘, 그리고 숨결을 하나로 모아
in unison
영력을 불어넣어야만
to ignite it.
비로소 다시 밝힐 수 있다 하였네
Let's begin.
시작하시죠
The Sunflare
얌염의 불꽃이
ignited?
피여올랐구나
Why is it dying again?
어찌하여 다시 꺼지려 합니까?
The demonic energy is too thick.
마기가 너무도 짙어
It won't catch.
불길이 채 번지지 못하는구나
Demonic energy is drawn to blood.
마기는 피를 탐하니
Once it smells blood,
피를 보게 된다면
it will be drawn away.
필시 그쪽으로 유인할 수 있을 터
No!
안 된다
Lifei,
려비야
live well.
부디 살아남거라
Get into Wuyue Court.
무월정에 들어가
Find your master.
네 사부님을 꼭 찾으려무나
Xiuyuan.
수원아
Lifei,
려비야
don't lose focus. Hold on.
한눈팔지 말고, 끝까지 버티거라
It's done.
됐다
Lifei!
려비야
Lei Xiuyuan.
뇌수원
Xiuyuan.
수원아
Wake up.
제발 눈 좀 떠 봐
Don't die.
죽으면 안 된다
I don't want to owe you again.
또다시 빚을 지고 싶진 않단 말이다
Lei Xiuyuan!
뇌수원
♪For a fleeting moment with you♪
♪그대와 함께할 찰나의 순간과 바꾸리♪
Xiuyuan.
수원아
♪Our fates intertwined, embracing yet fighting♪
♪얽히고설킨 숙명 속에 서로를 품고 스러지니♪
Wake up.
눈 좀 떠 봐
Wake up now!
어서 깨어나란 말이야
♪Obsessed and struggling, a thousand thoughts arise♪
♪집착 속에 아파하며 온갖 마음을 내어 보아도♪
♪Love sprouts again in this lifetime♪
♪이번 생의 애달픈사랑은 다시 움트네♪
♪No calamity can rival♪
♪수많은 겁난을 겪어도♪
♪The lingering thread of a fragrance♪
♪한 줄기 향기를 향한 미련은 떨치지 못하네♪
♪If the seal can't be broken, then let it go♪
♪얽매인 봉인을 풀 수 없다면차라리 내려놓으리♪
♪Where the heart finds peace, there is home♪
♪이 내 마음 편히 쉴 곳이 곧 나의 집이어라♪
♪Side by side, we fly through seas of clouds and break through the waves♪
♪비익조가 되어 구름 바다를 가로지르고 거친 파도를 깨부수니♪
♪The heart's ocean knows no shore♪
♪마음의 바다는 끝이 없어라♪
♪Always, at the very end of fate♪
♪언제나 가혹한숙명의 그 끝자락에서♪
♪Comes that one moment of defiance♪
♪끝까지 모질게 버텨내던 그 순간♪
♪In the human world or above, like flowing water♪
♪천상과 인간 세상사 모두 흐르는 물과 지는 ♪
♪And falling petals♪
♪꽃 같으니♪
♪Let this fleeting life be whatever it may♪
♪덧없는 이 허무한 삶을 그저 순리에 맡기리라♪
Congratulations!
축하하네
You've passed the trial!
시련을 통과했구나
Trial?
시련이라고?
You will become the rising young elites
너희는 장차 여러 선문의
of the immortal sects.
새로운 세대를 이끌 귀재들이니
With great cultivation
수위가 높을수록
comes great responsibility.
그 책임 또한 무거운 법이다
When the coming calamity strikes
훗날 참화로
and all life withers
만물이 시들어 가고
like kindling in a fire,
천지가 화로처럼 들끓을 때
you must stand firm as pillars,
너희는 굳건한 버팀목이 되어
for heaven and for the people.
하늘과 백성을 위해
Only by purifying the world with righteousness
호연지기로 천지를 맑게 정화해야 하느니라
can one truly be called a cultivator.
그래야 비로소 수선자라 할 수 있다
Now that you are about to leave the academy,
이제 너희는 조만간 서원을 떠나게 될 터
those who have found this path
이러한 도심을 얻은 자는
must hold to it
이를 굳건히 지키며
and never betray it.
평생토록 저버리지 말아야 할 것이고
For those who have not,
설령 얻지 못했다 한들
I hope you will reflect and act wisely
앞으로 살아갈 날들 속에서
in the days ahead.
더 많이 행하고 더 깊이 생각하길 바란다
Not bad at all.
다들 제법이구나
Quick reactions.
대처도 빨랐고
Fast on your feet.
도망치는 솜씨도 신속했어
In times of danger, you set aside your differences
위급한 순간에 편견을 내려놓고
and listened to Xiangxiang.
향향의 말에 귀를 기울일 줄도 알았으니 말이다
Especially
특히나
Jiang Lifei, Lei Xiuyuan, and Ji Tongzhou.
강려비 뇌수원 기동주 세 사람은
They risked their lives
타인의 안위를 지키기 위해
for the safety of others.
기꺼이 위험에 몸을 던졌지
Though a bit slow to act,
비록 과정은 좀 지체되었다만
they didn't disgrace the academy.
어쨌든 서원의 체면을 깎아내리진 않았구나
That said,
반면에 말이다
there were also those
위기의 순간에 동문들을 버려두고
who abandoned their fellows in crisis.
제 살길만 찾은 제자들도 있더구나
Zhou Shun.
주순
Dong Jiashuo.
동가석
They acted only for themselves.
행실이 이기적이니
They will not graduate.
결업을 불허한다
Also, Lanya harbored ill intent
또한 란아는 그 마음보가 바르지 못하여
and plotted against her companions.
동료를 모해하려 하였으니
She will be expelled
서원에서 파문하고
and never permitted to return!
영원히 입문을 허하지 않는다
Tongzhou...
사촌 오라버니
Yes!
예
I did go after her!
제가 손을 썼습니다
Because Jiang Lifei
그건 강려비가
doesn't deserve your favor,
사촌 오라버니의 총애를 받을 자격은 물론
nor does she deserve to enter any immortal sect!
그 어느 선문에 발을 들일 자격조차 없습니다
Go back to the Yue State.
너는 이만 월국으로 돌아가거라
Back to Yue?
월국으로 돌아가라고요?
Shouldn't I be entering Xingzheng Hall?
성정관에 들어가는 게 아니었단 말씀입니까?
Tongzhou,
사촌 오라버니
you let Zhao Mingli in.
조명례도 들여보내 주셨으면서
I can get in too, can't I?
어찌 저만 안 된다는 말씀이십니까?
Elder Zhenyun is missing.
진운 장로의 행방은 아직도 묘연하고
And Xingzheng Hall is in turmoil.
성정관 내부 또한 민심이 흉흉하다
Given your temperament,
네 성정을 보아하니
now may not be the right time for you to join.
지금 성정관에 드는 것은 합당하지 않구나
You're lying!
거짓말 마십시오
That's not how you really feel.
오라버니 진심은 결코 그게 아니지 않습니까
Tongzhou,
사촌 오라버니
you just don't want me to stay.
결국 저를 이곳에 남겨 두고 싶지 않으신 것이지요
You're afraid I'll come between you and Jiang Lifei, right?
제가 오라버니와 강려비 사이를 방해할까 두려우신 것이 아니십니까?
What's between us has nothing to do with Lifei.
우리 사이의 일은 려비와 무관하다
Go back to Yue.
그러니 월국으로 돌아가거라
Stay by His Majesty's side.
황형의 곁에 머문다면
You can still be the carefree princess
최소한 예전처럼
you used to be.
아무 근심 걱정 없는 소군주로 살 수 있을 터이니
Lanya.
란아야
Time really does fly.
시간이 정말 빠르구나
In the blink of an eye, we're graduating.
눈 깜짝할 사이에 벌써 결업이라니
Yeah.
그러게 말입니다
What do you guys think?
그런데 다들 어찌 할 생각이냐?
The master already asked.
어차피 사부님께서도 물어보셨으니
Have you decided
다들 어느 곳으로 갈지 정해 둔 곳이 있느냐?
where to go?
어찌 할 생각이냐?
What about you?
오라버니는 어찌하실 생각이십니까?
I
나는
was thinking we could go to the Dizang Sect together.
우리 모두 함께 지장문으로 갔으면 한다
Even though Gaolu is gone,
비록 고로는 이제 없지만
as long as we're together,
우리끼리 함께 지내야
it's some comfort.
서로에게 위안이라도 되지 않겠느냐?
Count me out.
오라버니께서 말씀하시는 우리에 저는 포함되지 않습니다
I haven't decided where to go yet.
전 아직 어디로 갈지 마음의 준비가 되지 않았습니다
You're not coming with us?
우리와 동행하지 않겠다는 거야?
Before, I was too young.
예전에는 제가 너무 어려
I just followed you and Ye around.
언니와 엽 오라버니 따라 이리저리 떠돌아다녔습니다
Now I'm grown.
하지만 이제는 저도 다 자랐으니
I want to make a decision for myself this time.
이번만큼은 제 스스로 뜻을 정해 보고 싶습니다
Gelin, we...
가림아, 우리
Lifei!
려비 낭자
I heard Wuyue Court is really hard to get into.
듣자 하니 무월정은 들어가기가 몹시 어렵다 하더군요
They haven't recruited from here in years.
벌써 여러 해 동안 서원의 제자를 받지 않았다는데
Who knows what's happening this year.
올해는 어찌될지 아직 알 수가 없습니다
I'm not worried.
저는 걱정하지 않습니다
I've got some aces.
저에게는 비장의 패가 있거든요
What's this?
그건 무엇입니까?
This is a pendant Qin gave me
진 사형께서 떠나실 때
when he left.
제게 주신 패물입니다
He told me to come to him at Wuyue Court.
무월정으로 오면 찾아오라 당부도 하셨지요
He's nice.
참 좋은 분이셨습니다
And this one.
그리고 이것도 있습니다
This one's even more impressive.
이건 더욱 대단한 물건입니다
It's from Elder Dongyang of Wuyue Court.
무월정 동양 장로께서 직접 제게 주신 것입니다
You're full of surprises.
려비 낭자는 보통 분이 아니셨군요
You'll get into Wuyue Court.
이번에는 반드시 무월정에 들어가실 수 있을 겁니다
Of course.
물론이지요
Definitely.
반드시 들어갈 것입니다
I have to.
기필코 들어가고 말겠습니다
After you.
자
Congratulations.
도형, 진심으로 축하하오
Thank you.
고맙소, 고맙소이다
After you.
자
Lei Xiuyuan,
뇌수원
think this through.
자네도 심사숙고해 보게나
Our offer is very generous.
우리가 제시한 조건이 제법 파격적이지 않은가?
[Luo Chengji, Lantian Sect] If you join the Lantian Sect,
[남천파 나성제] 자네가 우리 남천파로 오기만 한다면
we guarantee your cultivation will advance rapidly.
수위를 신속히 정진시켜 줄 것은 물론이고
You'll become a direct disciple
3년 안에 자네를
of the sect master within three years.
각주님의 친전제자로 만들어 주겠네
What do you say?
어떠한가?
Xiuyuan.
수원아
Lifei.
려비야
Wuyue Court's people haven't shown up yet.
보니 무월정 사람들은 아직 당도하지 않은 모양인데
Why not come to Xingzheng Hall?
차라리 나와 함께 성정관으로 가자꾸나
It's fine.
아닙니다, 괜찮습니다
I'll wait for Wuyue Court.
전 무월정을 기다리겠습니다
Your Highness!
소왕야 전하
If you two join my sect,
두 사람이 내 문하로 들어온다면
you'll surely accomplish great things.
장차 천하에 큰 뜻을 펼칠 수 있을 걸세
I see rare talent in you.
내 보니 두 사람의 골격이 비범하구나
If you join my sect
우리 문파로 들어와
and practice
우리 문파의 공법을 결합하여
our techniques diligently,
오로지 수련에만 정진한다면
your power
머지않은 날에
will increase significantly in no time.
공력이 크게 증장할 것임이 틀림없네
Mr. Shen.
심 선생님
Mr. Zuo.
원장님
You're a man of your word,
심 선생은 과연 신의를 지키는 분이시구려
coming to observe my new disciple selection.
내 새 제자를 뽑는 자리에 이리 친히 와주시다니
My daughter was once a master here.
제 여식이 한때 서원의 선생으로 지냈던 곳인데
Of course the Wanxian Sect had to come.
우리 만선문이 당연히 찾아와야지요
You're Jiang Lifei, right?
네가 강려비더냐?
Jiao mentioned you.
아초에게 네 이야기를 들었다
Would you like to join Wanxian Sect?
혹 우리 만선문에 들어올 생각은 없느냐?
Jiao is beautiful and impressive.
아초 언니께서는 아름다우실 뿐 아니라 무공 또한 뛰어나시니
Of course I'd be happy to join.
제 마음으로는 만 번이라도 가고 싶습니다
But
하오나...
for personal reasons,
제게 남모를 개인적인 사정이 있어
I have to enter Wuyue Court.
반드시 무월정으로 가야 합니다
Wuyue Court?
무월정이라…
By the way,
맞다
if those old men at Wuyue Court don't take you,
혹여 무월정의 그 완고한 늙은이들이 널 안 받거든
Wanxian Sect will always welcome you.
만선문은 언제든 너를 환영할 것이니 그리 알고 있거라
Thank you, Mr. Shen.
감사합니다, 심 선생님
Mr. Shen,
심 선생님
please go inside for tea.
안으로 드셔서 차나 한잔하시게
Wuyue Court's people are here!
무월정 사람들이 당도했네
Let's go.
가세, 가세
Let's go take a look.
어서 가서 구경하세나
[Wuyue Court]
[무월정]
[Guangwei, Wuyue Court]
[무월정 광위]
I'm Jiang Lifei. I plead to seek entry into Wuyue Court!
제자 강려비, 무월정에 입문하기를 간곡히 청하나이다
You're not much of a talent.
네 자질은 평범하니
Wuyue Court is not for you.
무월정은 네게 걸맞지 않구나
I'm Lei Xiuyuan. Greetings.
제자 뇌수원, 진인을 뵈옵니다
Lei Xiuyuan,
뇌수원이라
your Metal Spirit Root is unusually rigid and unyielding.
너는 금속 영근이 유달리 강인한 것을 알고 있느냐?
Xingzheng Hall's techniques are mostly domineering
성정관의 선법은 대개 강맹하니
and would suit you better.
실상은 그곳이 너에게 더 어울릴 터이지
But the way of the world dictates
하오나 이 세상의 이치란
that the rigid breaks first.
지나치게 강하면 쉬이 꺾이는 법
Sects like Dizang and Lantian aren't worth mentioning.
지장문이나 남천파는 논할 가치조차 없고
Only Wuyue Court's techniques
오직 우리 무월정의 공법만이
balance rigidity with flexibility. And that is what lasts.
강유를 겸비하였으니, 비로소 오래갈 수 있지
Would you like to join Wuyue Court?
우리 무월정으로 오겠느냐?
Yes.
제자, 따르겠습니다
But
다만...
I want to bring Jiang Lifei with me.
강려비도 함께 거두어 주시기를 청합니다
Jiang Lifei.
강려비라
What sets you apart?
네게는 어떤 남다른 재주가 있느냐?
I'm hardworking,
저는 고생도 마다하지 않습니다
sharp,
머리 회전도 빠르고
quick-witted,
총명하고 영리한 데다
respectful and caring, and resilient!
어른을 공경하고 아랫사람을 아끼며 매사에 끈기도 있습니다
I also have
그리고...
evil-warding beads from Immortal Dongyang.
동양진인께서 주신 벽사주고 있고
And this jade cicada from Qin.
진 사형의 옥선도 있습니다
I despise nepotism more than anything.
내가 살아생전 가장 싫어하는 것은 연줄을 앞세우는 자들이다
Wuyue Court will not take you!
무월정은 너를 받아들이지 않을 것이다
[The Eternal Fragrance]
[천향] [십사랑 소설 '천향인' 각색 작품]
♪I trade all the mortal world's splendor♪
♪내 인간 세상의 만장 부귀영화를 쥐고♪
♪For a fleeting moment with you♪
♪그대와 함께할 찰나의 순간과 바꾸리♪
♪Our fates intertwined, embracing yet fighting♪
♪얽히고설킨 숙명 속에 서로를 품고 스러지니♪
♪The hardest bond to balance♪
♪이보다 애달픈 연이 어디 있으랴♪
♪Obsessed and struggling, a thousand thoughts arise♪
♪집착 속에 아파하며 온갖 마음을 내어 보아도♪
♪Love sprouts again in this lifetime♪
♪이번 생의 애달픈사랑은 다시 움트네♪
♪No calamity can rival the lingering thread of a fragrance♪
♪수많은 겁난을 겪어도 한 줄기 향기를 향한 미련은 떨치지 못하네♪
♪With you, through mountains falling and seas turning to sand♪
♪산이 무너지고 바다가 모래가 될 때까지 그대와 함께하리♪
♪Withered branches burst into bloom♪
♪말라버린 나뭇가지에 다시 꽃이 피어나듯♪
♪Hand in hand on the Naihe Bridge♪
♪굳게 손잡고 나하교를 건너♪
♪Past the pagoda, in fine robes on galloping horses♪
♪부도탑을 지나 비단옷 걸치고 거침없이 달리리라♪
♪Always, at the very end of obsession♪
♪언제나 모진 집착의 그 끝자락에서♪
♪Comes that one moment of softness♪
♪내 마음이 스르르 무너지던 그 순간♪
♪Betrayed by all, I still reign supreme♪
♪세상에 버림받고 모두가 등 돌린들 어떠하리♪
♪With you, we melt into mist and haze♪
♪기꺼이 그대와 함께 환영으로 화하리라♪
♪I trade the highest heaven and endless clouds♪
♪내 구만장천의 붉은 노을을 딛고♪
♪For a fleeting moment with you♪
♪그대와 함께할 찰나의 순간과 바꾸리♪
♪Pierced by countless arrows, pain and illness pile on♪
♪만 개의 화살이 심장을 꿰뚫는 고통이 밀려와도♪
♪Yet I remain silent♪
♪그저 묵묵히 소리 없이 삼키네♪
♪Deep love and long yearning, a kiss falls into a dream♪
♪깊어가는 정과 그리움은 꿈결 속에 내려앉고♪
♪In the distant night, bitterness blooms♪
♪외롭고 긴 밤하늘 아래 쓰라린 꽃이 피어나네♪
♪The grand chapter is rewritten, startling the whole world♪
♪찬란한 운명을 다시 쓰니 온 세상이 경탄하누나♪
♪With you, through mountains falling and seas turning to sand♪
♪산이 무너지고 바다가 모래가 될 때까지 그대와 함께하리♪
♪Withered branches burst into bloom♪
♪말라버린 나뭇가지에 다시 꽃이 피어나듯♪
♪Hand in hand on the Naihe Bridge♪
♪굳게 손잡고 나하교를 건너♪
♪Past the pagoda, in fine robes on galloping horses♪
♪부도탑을 지나 비단옷 걸치고 거침없이 달리리라♪
♪Always, at the very end of obsession♪
♪언제나 모진 집착의 그 끝자락에서♪
♪Comes that one moment of softness♪
♪내 마음이 스르르 무너지던 그 순간♪
♪Betrayed by all, I still reign supreme♪
♪세상에 버림받고 모두가 등 돌린들 어떠하리♪
♪If the seal can't be broken, then let it go♪
♪얽매인 봉인을 풀 수 없다면차라리 내려놓으리♪
♪Where the heart finds peace, there is home♪
♪이 내 마음 편히 쉴 곳이 곧 나의 집이어라♪
♪Side by side, we fly through seas of clouds♪
♪비익조가 되어 구름 바다를 가로지르고♪
♪Break through the waves; the heart's ocean knows no shore♪
♪거친 파도를 깨부수니 마음의 바다는 끝이 없어라♪
♪Always, at the very end of fate♪
♪언제나 가혹한숙명의 그 끝자락에서♪
♪Comes that one moment of defiance♪
♪끝까지 모질게 버텨내던 그 순간♪
♪In the human world or above, like flowing water♪
♪천상과 인간 세상사 모두 흐르는 물과 지는 꽃 같으니♪
♪And falling petals♪
♪덧없는 이 허무한 삶을 그저 순리에 맡기리라♪